[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard
guys hello welcome I hope you are well I
hope you are well today's recommendation
as I love to give a recommendation right
before these podcasts go off is not in
the form of a TED talk or a book but in
a form of just kind of an overly obvious
thing if you are not doing something
extra in your life because of this
coronavirus to take care of yourself if
you haven't inserted new ways of taking
care of your mental health if you
haven't added a little bit of time to
your physical body movement if you
haven't started stretching if you
haven't started drinking more water if
you haven't tried to start noticing more
on your diet any of these things if you
haven't been putting in an effort please
do it just take care of yourself
self-love learn about why you need to do
it so it makes sense in your own mind
listen to that higher voice that's
within you it's so easy to just to get
comfortable because this is such a state
of of unknown right now it's such a
state of uncertainty it's it's it's
different it's it's easy to slip back
into to old habits it's easy to slip
back into old addictive behaviors it's
easy to slip into overeating any of
these things don't feel shame for any of
them we're all going through something
traumatic right now if you are a human
being on planet earth right now this is
the craziest [__] that's going on right
now we it's it's not even just about the
coronavirus it's about whatever life is
going to look
after this it's about the the mental
health effects of things right now it's
about the changes that are going to come
it's about the uncertainty that we're
feeling right now we are going to be
speaking of this time in our history
books it's okay to be feeling whatever
you're feeling right now just accept it
and take a look at it and forgive
yourself and just do a little bit extra
whatever you can whether that's writing
half a page of journaling in the morning
whether that's stretching for five
minutes before bed you don't have to be
like alright I need to get on my
seven-day workout plan and make sure I
don't miss it make sure I go two hours a
day go ham me I need to run 25 miles
today yeah just just little steps go for
a walk before you go for a run these
things are important just you know don't
avoid how you're feeling don't avoid
don't let the anxiety just project you
into more busy work take a second for
yourself so that's my recommendation
it's a weird times I'm going to keep
going with the podcast of course it's
just a it's just a weirder vibe you know
talking to people about their dreams
with this uncertainty is is different
I'm navigating where I want to where I
want to express myself and in what ways
around this whole thing I'm trying to
trying to get through it just like you
guys I suppose so anyway I hope you
enjoyed the episode please if you if you
did share it with a friend tell somebody
about it
we don't normally do these long intros
by the way I try to try to keep the
interest pretty short and sweet but I
just really wanted to put a pin in this
like if there's nobody in your life if
you're just gonna hang out by yourself
and you're just context in the same
people are seeing the same people on
Facebook whatever like if nobody new
life has told you you take care of
yourself [__]
you're worth it you're worth it take
care of yourself think of your highest
self think of you looking in the mirror
in 10 years in 20 years whatever it
looks like whatever our weird [__] after
this whole crazy coronavirus thing
whatever life looks like then just just
let yourself daydream use your
imagination
seriously just just let yourself sit in
that moment for a while and and be proud
of yourself and think back and say I'm
proud of myself because I took a little
bit of extra steps I just did a little
bit of extra work and I know that it
could add up so take care of your future
self by taking care of yourself now
anyway
let's roll boom but they're doing a
virtual version of like local musician
sets hmm for capitol block party and
she's like doing one of the sets it
sounds like which is cool that's so cool
yeah it's really cool that people are
doing stuff like this just like coming
together yeah like stuff happen I mean
it's it's definitely not I was texting I
was texting my buddy and I was asking
him how was he was like I'm virtually
raving and he was like you know it's
it's not bad he said it's just all about
mindset like you just got to go into it
like you know we got to bring the the
vibe with with us to this because
otherwise it's just people on a screen
DJing or it's people on the screen you
know dancing around or singing or
whenever you got to kind of bring the
vibe Do It Yourself hmm get that like
yeah it's cool though it's a challenge
yeah
just like what will happen to live music
after the sea it was live music was so
simple like before this like their like
the ability to at least like the
relationships that I've been lucky
enough to build there's a few places in
Long Beach that I could just message and
be like hey can we grab a spot on a
Friday in the next two weeks and they'd
be like yeah that sounds great you know
and so now it's gonna be but I wonder
what places will be able to pay artists
if at all thankfully we had like I we
don't like ask for a lot of money and we
would play for free in a lot of
situations just like knowing what's
going on and stuff I don't know she's
crazy dude like just what's gonna happen
to small businesses like that you know
all like this the servers are tender
Yemen like musicians DJs I don't think
we're gonna have more than 50 people in
the place for a while for a while that's
what I think too
I'm 50/50 even and yeah I mean but it
does give me hope for kind of like what
what
do where it's like like okay if it's
like if we're playing only breweries and
tap houses it's like you already can't
fit a hundred people in there so it's
like I wonder if like all live music
will be released on one tear or if like
the different tears or phases doesn't
they call it like I think they're
calling them if like you know what I
mean like yeah you might be you might be
first here I mean I feel like they could
scoot you over into the corner and I
mean I think that people like if you're
gonna he I think people are gonna be
like shockingly hungry for like hearing
real things in person yeah of course
more more than ever you know because
it's just I think I think that like we
are evolved and/or created to be like
social or commutative beings mm-hmm so
just naturally so I just think you know
music gathers excuse me pretty
comfortably um Eric let's a quickly
sidestep explain to anybody who doesn't
know first of all we'll explain that we
are outside if I haven't explained that
in the intro yeah and that is just a
race car
Dale Earnhardt jr. as my neighbor so
he's just driving around but I'm Eric if
we could just sidestep yeah I explained
to listeners who don't know who you are
and who rose tin is if you just like
explain kind of what's going on with you
guys
yeah I I'm Eric hi I'm not editing that
yeah I've I love music a lot roast Ann
is an acoustic folk trio with Jake
Wilson and Jacob Carroll Jake Wilson is
in an awesome band called the wild ish
who we have shared some really cool
memories with recently and as far as me
like my history with music like in high
school in college
the focus was jazz afterwards like I was
involved with some other music stuff
while in Seattle but it wasn't jazz but
jazz education helped plug me in and
then from there had some opportunities
to travel to a couple different cities
and record for other artists that like I
have no connection to like just being
hired to
play echoey sounds that go you know and
yeah I just like ambient sounds a lot
and I'm that's that's a lot of it that
works yeah what uh so what you were
saying we were talking about you guys
perhaps being able to to be the ones
that play you kind of explain maybe your
guys's vibe like genres maybe explain
roast and I think it's close
the closest thing we can describe it as
is like folky because it's definitely
acoustic led it used to have more like
electric guitar elements but I think the
more we played and the more songs we
wrote together so started off just like
me writing content and then then putting
a stuff together but then we started
writing more together and it just it
just seemed like folky stuff seemed to
fit better and to be totally honest like
I like singing singing has been a
learning curve and this genre seems to
fit with like my tone of voice best
where it can come off like at the
highest quality performance and like
make a lot of sense where it's like the
other stuff like you know I try to like
be like really edgy and stuff but it
would fatigue my voice quickly like all
the screaming I would want to do and
stuff and as although it makes a lot of
good emotional feelings for me and may
not be sonically pleasing to everybody
so just trying to continue to mold
together as a band and stuff but but
know we were talking about earlier was
live music like like how how and when
will who be able to play where yeah and
so we we historically have only played
small places right the I mean the
biggest place we've played was the
Tacoma McMenamin spanish ballroom but
then like the next day we were in
allensburg right like playing like a
super tiny room so it's like not I don't
know a we play small places mainly
breweries and stuff and like antidote
but their academic love moving in
Longview ash town was in the middle of a
move no one really knows what that's
about
yeah yeah it's that's super in the limbo
especially with all his kovat stuff
and then I don't know it's like so two
places that were pretty into live music
and I know that antidote will continue
doing it because they made good
relationships with a lot of musicians
yeah but there's like I mean who's gonna
want to pay artists I think that they're
gonna I think that a lot of businesses
too are going to start checking like for
more quality stuff if they're gonna pay
like I think I think like more like as
opposed to be like oh yeah I play covers
it'll be like I need to hear some
recordings before I booked you I think
that might start happening it's just
gonna be cut through it with all the
indie guys dude well you know there is
an artist that well I will not name but
he did he played at the lake last year
and the cello player was completely out
of tune he's saying terribly it was him
as acoustic in a cello it was awful and
I worked for Longview Parks and Rec
right and after I got hired on that
happened and stuff and it was during
like summer camp and stuff and someone
more my boss's ghost hey do you know
so-and-so and I was like yeah and they
go what do you think I was like I never
would have booked him I've known him for
years like that's not a good move and
they go well we really wish someone
would have told us anything and
ironically from that they've asked me to
put a contact list of like local bands
together which is kind of cool
so it's like you know like getting like
Alpine grace in there and the wild ish
and like so that way it's like if they
do a summer concert series or a
livestream series there we go
you know any means so it's taking that
community we've like mm made and we can
you know continue to use it you know
with the how the times have changed yeah
I just got a very bummed out cuz the
fourth of July isn't gonna happen we got
the lake oh it for sure won't happen you
know what's funny is I I would not
probably think oh yeah I'm like I'm
nostalgic about something that that I
was like that you like blame way over
but now I'm like reminiscing I maybe I
will go next to you I hope I hope it's
allowed and then you're looking for
parking and you're like you know what no
I hate this and then as I'm looking for
parking I Drive by and I smell like the
curly fries the elephant ears that's
like the thing that like that long be
people like we don't know about them
except for now do you have any stories
that come to mind of the being at Lake
sector we have on the 4th of July
yeah actually absolutely they I remember
oh I think it was actually last fourth
of July Jacob Westfall and tailored on
people that I play music with they
happen to be in town because Taylor's
family is Kelso native and so we they
really hey meet us at the food area and
I was like okay there's a lot of
nostalgic other memories too but this
one because it's recent just like
touches me more and like we just like
had like teriyaki chicken skewers and
fried rice and then we just sat and
listened to like some of the live music
and then us being musicians naturally
it's pretty easy like pick stuff apart
and have stuff to say but we were having
so much fun sitting in the grass just
Sun hitting us music was still good too
and just being like wow like they're
pretty good I've never heard of them
before they're from here that's crazy
you know and just having that kind of
conversation and just like just
blissfully enjoying what's happening and
not having to be like oh you know what
that guitar player could have fix his
tone if he cut some mids a little bit
which is normally what happens but not
having those intrusive thoughts what are
nice but other than that probably like
in like hop middle school or high school
like when you have a girlfriend you guys
need like matching bracelets you know
the flea market that's pretty good or
like I think everybody has a frisbee
with like one of their exes names on it
like the paint you know oh yes like
everybody had yeah every one of those
necessary those are the things like you
you never wouldn't you don't want that
and you've never been a time in our life
we like I would wish I had one of those
now and then you walk by that thing and
you see that they're doing it yeah like
we have to have we don't exactly know we
don't mean previously have one so we
gotta get one yeah yeah they're stupid
but we fall for it we fought for a lot
of things yeah so like a twelve dollar
elephant here we think that fried sugar
dough is like worth that but it's like
you go to like
stuffy's in the order like a gob and
that's what an elephant here is at what
point do we like hack the the human
taste bud be so it like so like dr.
pepper like they talked about their 23
flavors Michael about like incredible
yeah like the numbers increments like at
some point like we're so good at this
[__] scientists are so good like
coca-cola and Pepsi they can hire
whoever they want the smartest people
they can be like can you please tell us
how to make the most delicious soda that
really loves so much like at what point
do we just make the best stuff
everything everybody is just like they
can now put that scientist and
everything is just like it tastes all
like sugar
I think like every 20 years we realize
like oh [__] everything we've done is
wrong like there's like a 20 year
increments like I got like at one point
people were like oh we gotta like stop
using heroin as like cold medicine like
eventually that hit right and then I'd
like it all of our soldiers whoops and
then eventually you know eventually this
was an example I was talking with
someone about recently conservative
Christians used to like historically be
racist eventually right eventually they
all had to really go like Oh woops you
know I mean lights like I mean get and
now that's like in Christianity racism
as I clearly like not connected at all
right but for decades
hey like today hung out a lot right but
I don't know and I'm the people won't be
happy with how I said that and what I
said I think but not like starting drama
but just that is probably historically
inaccurate but I'm just a funny guy who
likes reverb like it's so a griever like
that's it like I'm not I'm not good at
like other things I just like this I
know I like what I like
how often Joe Rogan for example he'll
just he'll be going on about something
and we have like but listen folks I'm a
[__] dummy and he liked it right and
you know who be like I am a comedian in
I hate commentate people who fistfight
right guys and it's just you know yeah
you always gonna like it knock yourself
down that's the thing is I you know with
this podcast I was always afraid of like
stumbling over my words like oh [__]
it's gonna be devastating or like oh I
said the wrong thing but it's like I
don't care like if somebody like tries
to point me out I was like dude what are
you talking about how dare you say that
thing I beg no no I actually meant this
that's fine well think about I'll let
them misunderstand me like because I
don't have ill intention you know no and
then think about podcast is compared to
like like making like a clip or a
youtube video or something
mm-hmm like in long-form content it's
hard to edit a whole conversation and
censor everything because the art of a
pod
is that like we're talking off the cuff
like it's off the top of your head it's
what it's like on your mind it's how you
feel and sometimes we say things we
don't mean or fully understand or like
whatever and like that happens or you
might contradict something you said like
previously in life or another episode
and like that's not because you're wrong
or stupid or doing something wrong it's
just it's just like it's it's not it's
just that's not the intention its
long-form content you're having a
conversation right I mean it doesn't
need to be people wanted to take
snippets of things and like make it a
weapon but right yeah I feel like our
whole politics like our whole entire
puppet show whatever thing is a good
example of that like everybody just
trying to condense like well you said
this or you said these exact words like
even like the Trump said that you should
you know eat Lysol or whatever like the
you know if you could just realize that
he he doesn't mean like to actually
inject these things or whatever like
yeah it's just people wanting to twist
stuff for a political angle you think
something sounds stupid and worse and
stuff when it's like this like
coronavirus is 100% bipartisan and so
the fact that feels like politically
divided memes and stuff about everything
and that like the argument about our
well being is a political argument now
it is complete [__] honestly I I'm
frustrated by it because like I'm not I
don't have any politically charged
argument about the situation I just want
people to be safe want people to be well
I want things to move on but I want
things to move on the right way so it
doesn't have to return to a lifestyle
like this you know I like to return to
as much normalcy as possible and without
hurting any more people yeah it's yeah I
think it's an important time you know in
Park and Parks and Rec at the
after-school program we teach what's
called the four B's and I think like
they're so good like working with kids
has made me a better person because like
the cheesy things work they work for
kids and they work for adults too
so like the four B's are be safe be
caring be responsible and be productive
those are all four incredible character
traits that like that help you and the
people around you
every day constantly yeah right and so
like like be safe like be responsible
okay what am i doing to be clean and
permit myself and the ones around me
right now be caring what can I do for
other people like can i order and have
dinner delivered to a friend's house you
may be struggling or can I can I send my
friend money who needs help with their
bill can I know what can I do if you
happen to have those extra resources or
can you just like call and say hey I
love you and I'm thinking about you
because a lot of people need that stuff
right now right that stuff really does
work so across the board I always think
of like like you know your ear your
dorky ninth grade teacher who had those
like Garfield posters up still or what
every night like whatever they just do
man I totally wish that I feel like
there is some in my head from those but
yeah it was simplified you know like
look at my wall downstairs man that's a
lot of that [__] just as someone was
rambling about I was like what what did
they do say or like and I'm rambling
about to myself I'm like maybe that's
good I'll write that but like sometimes
yeah the essence it's funny we like the
reverse sometimes the essence can be
within you know one one or two sentences
yeah but at the same time sometimes it
can be because we're do you know think
about how we just started getting to
that that part of the conversation we
were talking about you know getting
taken out of context or like just right
Oh everything's okay man so that's like
the art of conversation really is an art
like it really is like me and the more
I'm doing these conversations at
Marvin's podcast it's like like you
watch like the thoughts that go through
your head as you're having the
conversation like as like for me as I'm
like you know like with Ag ADHD or
whatever like sometimes I'll be I'm like
open like 20 seconds that went by oh
dude I was in my own head like I was
thinking about something I wasn't
listening to them like that's like
that's like a weird thing to say you
know like but but then I'll you know you
bring it back you can yourself bring it
back and you you realize that you kind
of recollected it you kind of recalled
it mm-hmm
but it's just interesting it's just
interesting to see like not only how you
know I realized how my mind seems to
work differently than other peoples in
conversations but also also a super the
same like sometimes a weekend
we both think of the hang in there and
we both can agree that like those one
sentence things can just be super
powerful yeah millat of power and
simplicity and a lot of different things
and like a lot of different facets of
life like in music I found a lot more
power and some like some simplifying
songwriting there you who fade it out
like that's why I like a coat like
acoustic folk music right now like the
musical abilities in all of us like we
could access something way more intense
if you wanted to we can make the guitar
parts a lot more but doesn't feel the
same and there's something about like
having restraint restraint and intention
and like knowing like no this simple
thing carries so much more and like
knowing that and I think that also
happens like with dialogue I think that
also happens with gestures little
gestures you know like like like we
received not not a lot definitely not a
lot but we see like a little bit of
money from Spotify like under $100 typed
money you know you mean and I gave like
$40 of that to - tell us a-- who has
been doing like all of our photos and
stuff Morland because she has never
inity right one she's never asked for
money she's just like oh the exposure is
great it's like you're the one he's like
kind of blowing up in the Instagram
photography world like her film shots
like she's has a few like photos I have
over a thousand likes because like it'll
get reposted by someone long story like
she's like she's building this network
of really talented film photographers I
just an observation
I don't know facts about this but I'm
she's gained a lot of followers and her
likes are increasing and it's because
she's just like doing her thing and it
is so cool and so I I'm just thankful
that were able to work with her she's
really really smart and good at what she
does when was cool to bring that money
that you guys got from Spotify like full
circle you can just like oh yeah keep
feeding into your art her art and it's
like I don't even think about it I want
it want to keep going at both ends yeah
um what is spot if I've been like for
you guys you've like I know cuz you were
doing a lot of just band camp before
right band camp was like really
successful for what it was for us like
having that acoustic EP come out last
August and then get cold
actively collectively 2500 plays between
three songs which is like great that's
awesome that's like a huge there's
definitely a milestone for me personally
for my own music and stuff just having
the local community back you like that
and not like because there's so many
different parts of the community and
stuff I think we play well to like the
21 to 40 year old crowd I think we play
well to that and I think people connect
to it well yeah 41 year olds out yet
[__] yeah that their hate they didn't
not a huge fan
oh my birthday was yesterday
[Laughter]
your neighbors are probably upset I know
they're trying to work from home whoops
careless aim I got I made jokes and
laughed and snorted it well Spotify oh
yeah yes a band camp gave us some good
success and stuff and then we released
pragma on Spotify and February hmm and
after it was released we were able to
submit it for editorial selection and we
which is like a like curated Spotify
playlist like so like some people like
you can like you can even pay for slot
and playlists and stuff which is
interesting like labels will get people
on the on playlist it's like for like
1,200 bucks it's about the price you'd
pay for a good playlist but we got lucky
to get sucked it's like a couple of them
and like some playlists are like all the
time and then some playlists are like a
week long where it's like this week's
new release or whatever the you know a
title about this week something you know
and then next week it's a different
batch so but we got we went from fifty
five monthly listeners to to just under
4,000 and I fully credit that to Spotify
and algorithms we don't we don't know
3000 people and so that's really cool
well this so far I mean being on the so
far place so the so far sounds thing and
they've been like like promoting us to
like on their Instagram and stuff so so
give a little lowdown on that situation
so assume right I mean if we're not
going to air the other podcast that we
had it all
we only other podcasts we don't have
recoup it the whole thing but yeah but
it was it was right before the the
coronavirus oh yeah it was just just the
attitude was just entirely different
there's a lot of things that were both
about different force well the the hard
thing is that we had built up a lot of
momentum January through through
February you know we played like just
under 20 shows starting to travel a
little bit playing things that are
bigger than we normally could and then
we're about to play this show called so
far sounds which is that they do like
secret shows and a little over 400
cities around the world people you know
buy tickets that's used by 120 people
max in a room and they literally like
blankets and pillows on the ground right
like people who have cool homes yeah
right check them out on what are their
instagrams so far digital in so far yes
just if you use so far sounds that's the
main one which is like the corporate one
and then you can also just search cities
that you live in you're like so far
Portland's so far Seattle and then if
you go to the website you can just I
type in the zip code that you're living
in and the pull up shows that are near
you and stuff and they usually book
things two months in advance and they do
a show every city doesn't show like once
or twice a week Seattle would do
multi-site stuff like they do two or
three shows in one week or in one day
it's like you would pay it you'd pay for
a ticket and then you would get told to
go to like this address like like the
day of the show you'd be sent the
address like you don't know where you're
going until then which is another cool
part of it it's always like a cool place
of business or someone's really cool
like living room and the hills of
Seattle or something done it you know
really cool things and so through their
photos oh yeah it's really cool it's
pretty sick it's it's definitely
something that we were excited to be a
part of thankfully they like promoted
our livestream the first one we did back
in April oh it's still April maybe we
did it in March it's I remember when we
did it man yeah it's different right
yeah I have no concept of time right now
I just know that it I am just happy to
not be inside my house Sharon Birds it's
crazy that's wild so much green yeah
that's awesome back here so so what
happens when they put you guys on a
playlist like yes only this were you
guys on
so the the platelets so there's a song
writing playlist but the playlist that
so far put us on was like artists will
miss this month or whatever so they
posted all the artists that got canceled
another cool thing so far sounds did is
they paid us for this show we didn't
play the all the artists they cancelled
they send a hundred bucks too which is
just a really cool gesture knowing that
like most musicians that's their
livelihood not a lot of income in music
so that's why there's a lot of artists
relief funds right now we don't need
that because we all either have our own
resources or like for like for me I was
lucky enough to be on Washington State
Unemployment because working for the
city and the school district so it's
like that's fine like I don't need to be
a part of an artist Relief Fund I don't
need money from stuff like that but the
so far sounds things just a separate
thing that was cool but yeah and then
like with Spotify stuff what's
interesting about playlist placement is
that it's easy to get excited about it
it's easy to get to get excited about
numbers like I was pretty thrilled about
it at first but then when I was able to
get in contact with a representative and
talk to talk about the details of our
analytics and stuff because we were
talking about the next song release May
10th which we have a song coming out May
10th
called warm eyes soft skin I like it a
lot I hope you do too it's a fun one
beautiful yeah it's good I think it's a
good page turn I think it's a I think
it's really it's I think it sounds a
really grown you know what I mean he
also listener right now if you listen to
this on Spotify or wherever just you can
still listen to this you don't deposit
just go over and type in ROS tan ro se
ya ta N and then hit follow and then you
don't you don't even have to listen to
songs right now but you can follow and
then you'll just see right when they
released on May 10th
yeah May 10th absolutely thank you yeah
and that's another thing it's like so we
have like several thousand plays or
whatever but so around thirty percent
are listening to it all the way through
so like so sixty to seventy percent of
people are at least like skipping it
after the halfway mark so and then our
followers brought two hundred and
forty-one
halfway mark that's how they measure
that if it's there's like there's
different plot points they can measure
stuff by oh right analytics can go real
deep apparently there's no yeah
I don't want to look at it on this
podcast it's annoying yeah it's it it
hurts kind of here it doesn't we're
thing to your pride so that then I I I
just I already I already miss like band
camp only antidote this Friday type
stuff and not that like not that words
anything bigger than that now because
we're not but I just like I'm sorry
nothing like oh hi am I supposed to
manage things differently like what do I
do moving forward but we were talking
about like the original like well we did
at the band did a podcast with you right
the biggest thing was about eliminating
expectation and then focusing on
community I think in recent months it
had that has been absent from for us and
I think just finding ways to refocus on
both those points I think will help get
rid of that noise and the peripheral
vision about like oh you're on a
playlist blah blah it's like okay well
we gotta hope that the second song does
so we gotta hope that the second sound
of successful or it's gonna look really
crappy and we're gonna feel you know so
it's just about eliminating expectation
just continuing to record and write and
just put music out there like you love
you know you feel good about we had how
do you balance because like you do like
you know let's say the man I mean yeah
the manager side of this tooth like
you're you're writing the lyrics and
stuff so you have to like manage this
artistic side of your of your view on
everything like all of it but also you
kind of have to like think of it like
you do have to look at the numbers like
it you know you know artistically is
healthy to like [__] numbers or
whatever right there is a kind of a part
like this world that we have if you kind
of want people to hear your music you do
have to kind of play the the manager
game like how do you manage yeah I think
I think Spotify it doesn't mean a whole
lot the best way to grow your numbers is
to play live Instagram is a good example
of that we haven't gained a lot of
followers because of Spotify but every
time we play somewhere out of town we
gain like maybe 15 or 20 followers now
we only have like 220 followers not a
lot but it increases naturally and we
have it like we have anna hashtag to
single photo for example like this is
big there's no outside source to like
just grab onto and go oh that's an extra
like like we have to seek it out to find
it mm-hmm
and I think that's been a really
important part of the brand for Oh Stan
it's just like like we're just offering
this and if you like it awesome we love
for you to be part of this community and
and it's okay if not like there's like
there's no there's no spotlight to
compete for there's like just understand
that we got here just like being who we
are and stuff and that we're still gonna
enjoy playing with a bunch of like our
local like favorite bands and stuff like
that there's nothing like the numbers
may help us be an opener somewhere
someday or something you like in
Portland OR Seattle and we can cross
that bridge when we get there but guess
what that's probably about six months
out so ok you know so I'm not I'm not
really worried about I don't wanna say
I'm not worried about the numbers but I
feel like I would almost be lying I had
to stop myself I I naturally worry about
it but it's just I don't think you've
been able to keep a good balance of
these things like yeah and I'm not
really doing a lot of inner dialogue to
do it I think there's like I just had
like a sensor where it's like I can feel
like if like I can be typing on a post
that could be on my second or third
sentence and be like this is pretty self
glorifying and I was like I'm not gonna
post after all yeah and so just like
just recognizing like oh this doesn't do
a lot like it's good to celebrate and
inform people of something but it's like
okay why are you trying to like rub this
in or eat why are you trying to make a
statement because if so that doesn't
help the brand of the band it doesn't
help the integrity of the other two
bandmates that you're with you know what
I mean and so it's it so you I don't
know being in a band is nice because the
creative side and the marketing side
becomes a lot more selfless like I have
to I greatly care about my jakes
including you but like but but I care
about making sure maintain the integrity
that has rose tan and not having that
being compromised and knowing that they
are a part of that integrity and that
they have helped to build up my own
personal integrity right so it's just
not stuff that I'm willing to sacrifice
because I mean right now is the first
time I've like liked myself as a person
in a while and I know like this kind of
mindset is what's like what helped
propel that right you know like having
having fruitful creativity has helped me
be a better person and froufrou
fruitful creativity also meant being
like honest with myself about where I'm
at with the
process is knowing that I have like a
cool number on Spotify in eight months
that really might not be there at all
and so like the the our job is just to
continue doing what we're doing like
that like playing at the Spanish
ballroom in Tacoma that's a cool thing
but it's not like we only played venues
that big after that that was a moment a
cool stop on the road and you keep
traveling mm-hmm all right the Spotify
thing that's cool that's awesome and we
keep going right and we'll see what
happens for moving forward yeah you know
I'm hopeful I want I mean I'd be lying
if I said I didn't want success I do I
do
but but all of my favorite artists had
success come in a very organic way and
their success is not like a blow-up
success what being put on the radio it's
like like there's a career in music and
being this good songwriter you know what
I mean like you can build this
reputation over years and I'm just
willing to take the time to make it
happen right for once yeah you can't you
can't oh this is a good quote a lot of
people want to emulate like the final
product of their vision and stuff but
they want like skip the process right
right we're we're nowhere near through a
process of anything right so we can't
skip anything we're gonna keep writing
this out and just enjoy it for now
that's what it's all about it anyway man
yeah I get to this I mean at a time like
this you know being quarantine is is a
reminder that that's what it's about
anyway it's like being able to see your
friends being able to play just a Friday
show at a local brewery yeah I think
there will be a time that you realize
that you look back and like oh yeah
those are the good old days that's what
they write man no that's I mean you get
you guys are doing a great job of I mean
just because I know you guys personally
you do the job of genuinely enjoying
this like it's not like it's work it's
not like it's like okay oh right on to
the next one like it's you have a
seriousness about it but you also have
this enjoyment like you guys do enjoy
talking to people about about your music
afterwards and oh yeah Manning people
and go into these new places and getting
in the van and having having the long
bro - bro conversations like the whole
ride over the mountain you know so yeah
that's what it's all about it I drove
into Ellensburg with Jacob Carroll last
time that would I love that you mention
that because I was so cool but most of
the drive if not all of it
from Longview to Ellensburg
right no music and we didn't need it
like we would talk about stuff or we
just enjoy the silence and the drive
like cuz cuz like there's such a
fulfilling feeling like when you like
we're traveling to a small town to just
go play music and that's it we're not
saying like well we're wrong to like
we're not embellishing it we're not on
tour we're not doing this in that we're
going to go play for 25 to 30 people and
and we love those people that's why
we're going back again this month so
like just like we we go to engage with
the same people because we made friends
and these friends want to hear us again
and we want to go play for them right
and we don't make money from Ellensburg
shows we we've hit financial losses on
both mm-hmm you know I mean cuz you rent
a vehicle and you get out there and you
may get paid but that payment covers
like two thirds of the vehicle and I can
you all this kind of stuff so listeners
by the way if you didn't know most the
time when you see a band well not most
the time but sometimes when you see a
band a lot of times they're really not
getting paid out of the place like that
no jar just like no maybe a 5 maybe a 1
whatever you got and there's some places
like I mean it's gonna change now
there's been some like McMinn immense
like they pay musicians pretty well you
know II mean casinos pay musicians very
well yeah you don't I mean I can go play
for two nights with with a couple of
friends and stuff playing guitar just
and it's their music their set
there's tell me what key it's in every
song I just like fiddle faddle around
I'm gonna walk with a 600 bucks
you know you mean and I'll get put up in
a hotel room but you're in the middle of
nowhere and it's a drive for four hours
but that's what music like is there's
this really huge like glorification of
this final product that is a very small
narrow area of music which is like wow
what a big successful rapper that's like
the big brand like every ad for becoming
a musician or be a producer or learn how
to mix it's all based on hip-hop and rap
now which is like fine let's it's fine
it's what's popular and that's great
but like like music stores are closing
because no one wants to hold an
instrument right now and take the time
to learn and do that and it's because
like this like there's this weird quick
gratification glorification of this
thing there's a few artists that I know
like that I work with outta state and
stuff where it's like their product has
greatly diminished muted musical value
because they've wanted it to conform to
a vision or emulate a product that like
is not they like they're not that yet
and stuff
and so it's like you used to play guitar
like all the time like you need to do
that and I can only like identify with
that because I've avoided playing guitar
for a few years because I was like
people don't want to hear that and it's
like well when you do what you're best
at people will want to hear that it's
just about like right time the right
place you know I mean I turned 27 in May
and it took until now to have like a
good a good hit musically I couldn't
good like for myself my solo stuff i
haved I've done stuff with other people
and that's great but I wanted something
that that I did with with well I made it
sound like me it's not me it's you know
everyone else around it and the whole
team and stuff but well I mean I guess
the initial jump was your writing so
it's kind of that's what that that's why
that's what I was trying to slow Stan
was birthed from your first like it was
your idea first it's not like you're
claiming it no no but but it is like you
know like a lot the songwriting and
stuff you know it comes from personal
experiences or it's like trying to
overcome like stuff that I've avoided
mentally and emotionally or or stuff
that you're like you're projecting it
into the future and stuff like where my
soft skin is really cool because it
talks about I don't just talk about
something like that I like that I think
I like really want right now but it's
also like it's not to excuse me I burped
it's not to anyone though you know what
I mean right
okay like it's a it's like projecting
mm-hmm and that's why I'm a tenth yeah
yeah yeah so that's like a really
important thing for me and that's we
talked about that earlier like there I
have a good mentor I can like send some
stuff to and he will recommend like
grammatically altering this or write
about the same subject from a different
perspective slash narrative and and
that's really opened things up and then
also knowing that like I can't write
about the same thing over and over again
and expect myself to be better or the
music to get any better
woo you know powerful yeah so so the
progression has been like natural and
spend good like like that's why I like
to this point I guess how I go like I
like Who I am I want things that I like
and these are good things yeah you know
and I think that think these songs are
good songs I think there will be better
songs in the future I think well I will
be continued to become a better singer
hmmm I think we will all become better
guitarists together I think songwriting
as a group will become better it's just
it's just aging stuff with time like we
haven't even been a band for a year like
we were technically a band starting in
October you know so well I mean you guys
are going through like this weird thing
like any band going through anybody
going through any of this is gonna be
changed there so but going through this
like you guys have still been able to
like communicate you're still great
friends you're still practice which
other you were able to do a couple live
streams you're able to like write you
know you're able to you know maintain
this and stay hopeful for like oh yeah
this is course this is what we're still
doing yeah and there is like there's
that small voice where it's like all
things will never be the same music oh I
love this and that but all all that I
know is that like it's like waking up
every day and figuring out like that day
and stuff and so like I'm kind of
projecting and wanting to like you know
like like some places are already
rebooking for the fall like we're
getting e-mails back which is cool but
even still like who I mean just who
knows it's it's it's really hard to be
in a place where you don't have control
over something or the thing about
booking shows and stuff like that it's
like I can send them recordings that I
know we sound good and I can perform
with these guys because I know we do a
solid half hour to 45 minutes anywhere
we go you know what I mean on stuff like
that and you know when you're not able
to practice routinely already know when
you're not able to do all these things
you know like we're gonna do another
livestream on May 1st that's like and I
really hope it works
you guys remember like I'm enough to
look over all of our lyrics right like I
tried doing a live stream by myself my
personal Facebook page and I forgot the
lyrics to most of our songs oh no you
know like at least a verse you know
what's weird how that works
muscle memory man yeah you know the
guitar parts are there because that's
like the best the best thing that I know
what to do but it's the lyrics it's that
sound was terrifying with headphones on
not know I just yeah it did double
screeched it yeah dude I thought was
like a pterodactyl landing on like the
top branch or something exciting yeah if
there's savage birds out here are there
I want one anyway well yeah so I mean
it's just a different area for music and
Rose tan but I look forward to it I'm
excited about it they're good people
they've been supporting me I love them
the people that I've been supporting us
we love them it the whole Spotify thing
feels fairly undeserved but like like
cool for now yeah and just like I said
Lee he's got to keep going to the next
thing you can't I can't spend too much
time on that cuz like because then cuz
then like it like I shared it because I
was excited about it you know like when
we had like our first thousand I was
like this is cool and all and they just
already click I was added to his group
chat of musicians like from the Texas
area and stuff and like right when I add
to the stories like then all of them
started by adding their play plate
spotify stats to their stories and I was
like oh like I'm not trying to like do
that and like I don't want us all to be
doing that like you know what I mean
like all this one's like oh he's sharing
I gotta show mine too it's like nah it's
not just like one little proud moment
like oh this is like a thing that
actually like this isn't kind of a
little bit more than a spark I've never
had that before that's what I reckon and
it's I was just shocked to see that even
a moment of like wanting self
gratification
there's still seems like volatile toxic
behavior and I was I would it was good I
liked seeing that because it made me
want to lean into like the good stuff
we're already doing okay good and not
that we won't say things but like I just
now net I just know now it's like okay
that number exists on Spotify and not on
our social media
mm-hmm like if you go see that number
cool but like there's nothing gratifying
about posting that like we got like I
need to like okay that's not you know so
and that's like that's why I like for
example we don't post stuff like that
like on our Instagram posts maybe
stories like the posts are always like
thoughtful photos and something that
probably have to say you usually commit
a lot of time into Instagram yeah yeah
even though it's like like I said not a
lot of followers but it's just about
packaging things away that you like like
I care about like we care about right
how things look sound and feel and and
we care enough to make it honest - right
so we've had a ton of our conversations
about about that like just the I feel
like we both I mean
we don't have the same like haste I'm
more rambunctious sure but no I
appreciate your style in your art in
your eye towards our inial like you'll
take the long time to get the perfect
angle on on the corner of the photo you
know oh thanks yeah and I appreciate
that I think that's cool I think you
know I probably been listening to too
much AI [__] but I feel like little
stuff like that is like that's that's
gonna be hard to replicate you know like
when you like what's different about
humanity like what's so special about
you know like what creativity what is
that all about why can't we just
reproduce it with the right algorithm
once again it's about having like you
can emulate that final product but you
can't emulate the process yeah yeah yeah
it's it's a really weird thing to like
think about but you can keep cycling
that sentence through like you'd be like
you'll be meditating just thinking about
that and being like dang like what am i
emulating what I should I be walking
through more it's very interesting it's
it because it can be like beyond music
it can be it can be anything
mm-hmm I looked at a few situations
socially where I was like oh you know
really nice it's really good it's just
good till I kind of have those like
moments where you you know not like full
like cognitive wake up like coming
online it's crazy like sometimes it's
just nice to be like oh yeah I should
change how I do that
yeah it's enough to be crazy you have to
like anyway that's that that's that Jake
and that's right you don't want it you
don't want to talk about ripping the the
cord out of the back of your neck like
in the matrix you just wait so and I
will tell you you know I'm gonna I'll go
I'll go I'll go out on a limb and just
say it so yeah I've done LSD and that's
exactly what he feels like I feel like
there's a hose connected to the back of
my head mmm and it's really insane and
like I just feel like you're I can this
I don't know describe it with words I
already feel weird like on the back of
my neck go something it's weird it does
like it's a weird thing I can't wait
till it's a it's a normal thing you know
I think maybe five years it's already
you know the psychedelics are doing a
lot of work for people with depression I
mean like it with with anxiety with all
these things that helping a lot of
people out I think it'll be a normal
conversation people will be able to like
understand what you're talking about
they're like wait right unplugging what
from your what yeah but he have you
watched the Matrix series lately like
you like with the rascal ears
wouldn't past five years I've seen them
yeah okay okay that's me I mean cuz II
cuz like I knew that it was a cool story
and I loved the story like the waking
from reality whatever but uh like yeah
definitely um but uh I think just like
the I forgot how badass mm like the the
fight scenes were oh dude absolutely
dude come on man so savage [__] I'm
playing early to mid-2000s videogames
right now and I'm like yeah I get it
it's yeah and you know what like mo and
anyone whose individual games now they
all playing an Xbox 360 that's so stupid
like you can't even blow a ball online
you can't anything it's like you know
what people are allowed to like things
and I like spending my time doing this
right now and just kind of like you know
ordering these kind of snacks and
getting them delivered to me I'm having
a great Tuesday like why not right why
I'm like I'm allowed to do that not like
it's and but it also but like man it
sounds so stupid bring it back like
those four B's though it's like you're
allowed to like things but it's being
aware that's like not affecting other
people negatively - right you know
that's actually funny because that's I
was gonna bring it back to the four B's
next because I was gonna say like what
what have you been doing you know I want
to just make sure during this quarantine
thing I was going to make sure like do
you have any mental health advice like
any like little tips and tricks of like
things that maybe you've done or thought
of doing or even just like you learn a
lot teaching kids like yeah we're tips
and tricks a my biggest piece of advice
is the next time you put your hands on
your hips and you exhale really hard
inside your house you're supposed to go
for a walk like that's that's a huge
thing like out like I like I'll just
exhale and just look around my room like
well what am I supposed to I'll go
outside dummy it's nice outside what am
I gonna do move walk with your legs and
then turn around eventually and then
come back what why is it have to be like
you have to go meet someone somewhere
you'd have to go complete a task and
walking back and forth while doing
something you have gotta go mind is
always like trying to assign us tasks
you need to complete this why do I need
to complete this I think we it but we
don't really have this back layer of
because I need I know that it's
important because I know that I'll feel
better afterwards and I know that I'm
better decisions when I feel little
better I'll know that a-hole it'll
remind me like also looking at our
phones and [__] looking at screens being
inside like walking around look up look
around move [__] eyes around move
you're moving your feet get your blood
flowing yes so many even like it's like
you do yoga in the morning but even
something as simple as like you just
find like a basic like set of stretches
it doesn't have to be like this hole
right like long thing to just like stuff
that gets the blood flow moving and and
for me I have a plate I have a playlist
that I've designed that like like the
first five songs well they play us to 35
minutes I give myself that half hour
like I'm gonna wake up I might like you
know I might take a DAB or something um
I'm gonna
III arranged these lights in my room
till I give me a certain vibes I'll
crack the blinds open the window enjoy
myself and then at a certain point I'm
like I'm not gonna play video games yet
still the morning right and then you
know go for that walk then or something
like that or lately I've been doing
drives her drove to Mount st. Helens the
other day right and that was nice I
drove to the beach the other day like a
while ago I bought a kayak oh yeah have
you got to use it yet not yet I was
still being shipped Oh shipping keeps
getting like pushed back further and
further I thinks because the size of it
and like the now not essential it is
yeah it's the bajas gonna be beat up
because people like this guy [__]
about a kayak right now but that's the
everything is like quarantine has taught
me that uh like that I that I am okay
alone Wow
like it what do you mean so with like
with friendships and relationships I
like I will fight tooth and nail to stay
around someone because I can't stand to
be alone and because like I'm not I
don't want to like have a new friend or
a new person relearn Who I am like
what's the point of that what's the
point of going through all that again if
we you know any mean and then having the
absence of relationships and friendships
not that like you're not friends with
people right now but you have a lot of
time to yourself right I I think I'm
changing good parts of me during the
quarantine like I got excited to be
social again so I can be like a more
positive person I think I was already in
the right direction Rico
but I think that I'm learning more
things now I think like like I can enjoy
time by myself as opposed to like just
like feeling really dark and heavy with
emotion and feeling guilty about this in
the past or this and that and just like
acknowledging things that have happened
in the past as like final moments like
they're like that you can't like you can
relive them but you can't redo them so
what about it right and and all these
kinds of and that and there are all
different facets of your life - I can be
even like like there's not like you can
like think back to weird things that
happen in a classroom in middle school
you know it's like you have those weird
stories that you're having in fifth
grade when I fired and I held my nose
and it was on a plastic chair oh no I
was so loud minutes during a are eating
my friend Evan man [__] Evan Evan
Pugh montón man he [__] sitting next
to me he just did I remember he did some
sort of like oh my god just oh what a
great guy I couldn't handle it though I
got on blame him like it was I don't
know where school no no one no kid would
no no here's the most devastating thing
I think I've told this story but the
most devastating thing is I looked at my
teacher for help and helped me with my
eyes and he couldn't help this he wasn't
cracking and laughing but he couldn't
help them and it was just everybody
simply he's reading a book - it's just a
perfect fifth grade class I flipped my
eyes cuz it helped me and he said I'm
sorry I can't hold this laughing and I
got betrayed I just loved said help me
with my eyes I'm like I've been there at
one point we've all said help me with
your eyes like what there's a teacher's
job it's yeah cool I actually you know
yeah I think that's that's great solid
advice yeah I mean we go going outside
listen to more music discover music put
yourself in listening situations that
you didn't find yourself uh click on a
different playlist on you normally would
or something like that or as opposed to
like clicking shuffle on a bunch of
singles that well maybe you like this
band go ahead and listen to a full album
of something yeah I think flaw album
listening is dying
but also good album writing is dying mmm
my cab people doing singles in like oh I
have 12 songs but it's an album l like a
lot of rap albums that I'm listening to
it's a lot of not like writing and
programming through and stuff like that
right like there's only maybe three or
four albums I've heard in the past five
years I've been like I'm gonna listen
this album from start to finish all the
time and that's you tell me I have to
tell you first I'm gonna cut you off
really I'm sorry okay I'm gonna tell you
first my album that I would recommend
because I feel like if you have good
album recommendations you sure about
here okay mines Haydn James his most
recent album mmm it's a blue album cover
nowhere to go perhaps Hayden Hayden
James Dean James yeah hey che ydn hey
hey what yeah yeah but his most recent
album named James front-to-back every
day I can't just listen to one song
Shane and I both it's fantastic between
us between us yeah yeah yeah so that's
my album that's but what what is your um
there I would probably have to say
there's a band called golden days Daz
where I've been pretty obsessed with the
work they've done there but my most
recent discovery this uh black indie
artist more more his music is like so
soulful and he has like a really floaty
voice but you don't really expect from
someone to approach this genre in this
angle but he like has like R&B soul with
like indie tone in style and it's really
really cool the I think the EP is
self-titled but maybe it's not but any
widget mor mor it's one word more like
that it's good oh you would really like
it a lot
could this and it's actually an EP that
I have like glazed over and have skipped
in past days but then all of a sudden I
realized that I have separately liked
three of the five songs on my lot on my
library and I was like oh maybe I do
like this album and I went back to it
and I was like oh this is a whole thing
right so but also just a palace life
after is like the best album I've heard
in a long time that album is still I
still listen to it once every day's from
start to finish
Bath's Roma plasm geotech traverse'
that's a big one evan de l'homme and I
listen to that one a lot
those last year were great mornings
super good mornings yeah geotech
traverse' is like the best like Oh is
there sunshine and are you getting in
your car cool here's like here's like an
hour of like really melodic low low
intensity house music that you can just
like cruise on for every was that what
what was the long there was like a
25-minute long mix her song
automatically on frequency
oh yeah MT otic so what's crazy is I
think I'm gonna told you about this but
I was actually driving up a few months
back maybe four months back I was
driving up Mount st. Helens or to cold
water lake to go hiking in that song
came on and I was like Alf I'm gonna
[__] let it play I'm driving up right
now and I was like so really the Sun was
literally rising bro I have a photo that
I could show you was like between 4:00
and 5:00 a.m. I think I don't
it was super early but um and I let I
didn't let the entire thing play but I
let it probably like 16 minutes in or
something yeah man
it's a lot of the drive but it but it
was did yeah it's weird like frequencies
like it's just like a [__] tone but
you like it's there's still a tempo -
they're still rhythm pure they're
somehow still uh but like it's so weird
like how do we understand that like how
do you you know that's it's so yeah well
being to it I mean there's I think
there's the thing about ambient music
the reason why I like it is the lack of
dialogue allows your internal dialogue
to really turn up even if it's not busy
it's like gonna be pretty intentional
like you're telling yourself things
you're thinking of memories you're
feeling something and it doesn't have to
be that deep something can just sound
pretty and you're enjoying it but like
when you listen to something pretty
we trained podcast outside also by the
way in the summer anyway listener the
rule is when it when a car when a train
goes by you have to drink that's our
barbeque rule so cheers from across the
table I'll feet apart buddy Cheers
Deborah much I like that beer yeah it's
like it's like a life sippy cup
hey hey Z Bale it uh it almost comes off
like a like a light hey Z like it has
like a lightness to it you don't mean
like we're some IPAs I can't that big
like weight feeling this is like light
easy to drink it's light on the throat
like like the aftertaste on the throat
yeah it doesn't give you that like
sometimes an IPAs a little crispy on the
throat yeah we're like gnarly and in
like bitter and sour almost from the
hops
I wonder what like a beer connoisseurs
like how they actually talk like what
what is that proper terms cuz like I'll
say bitter and I'll say hoppy and I
don't know what I'm actually saying no
you're nailing it probably it's not as
complicated I think there's a great
video I watched where's like a beer
expert like picks between expensive beer
and not expensive beer like and like I
guess the price points and stuff and
he's like talks about all's and stuff
and talking about maltiness and tartness
and in age and hops and all these things
it's like you like like watching that
helps you identify with stuff a little
better hmm yeah it's pretty cool because
he's talking about stuff like with beers
that you drink so you're like oh that
word works for that kind of beer and I
understand why because he's explaining
with him that feels or tastes like right
yeah it's it's worth watching I really
love watching stuff like that that like
can improve my conversations with other
people like when it's like oh my keep
doing the same thing yeah that I it's
fun to be able to like oh you almost won
like rewind it sometimes like oh yeah I
want to remember that [__] word yeah
like when it because it's it's enjoyable
you know this is an obvious thing but
it's worth stating it's enjoyable to you
not only like get into what you like but
be able to like properly articulate what
what you mean around like interests that
you have so when you meet somebody else
like out of the blue or you have a
friend who has the similar interest you
can you can really like dig into the
conversation about it and feel like a
new kind of joy together you know by
talking about those things
what have you wave you one of you in
Shaylee or or you just separately what
have you guys been watching during this
whole quarantine stuff it I thought
you're super into right now like
Benjamin and binging we have been the
Marvel movies so yeah we are on and I
think where are you going like are you
going chronologically we went
chronological let's go okay the order or
no no okay so to know so I think we I
think we're in the order that they came
out okay so so I don't know it's time
not not timeline that line that's why it
was like released great not like but so
we just watched the one after Captain
Marvel is I think the most recent once
not Civil War like when they have you
watched these have you watched it not a
lot of them to be honest I mean like and
I'm I don't have anything native say
about him just like superhero movies
just don't do it for me oh wow
okay so dude I'm obsessed so we pretty
much watched all of them now we like
binge watch them
we both love them like the movie style
I've always been obsessed with like the
hero's journey clink I've always had
this like like like why doesn't
everybody see that the these you know I
don't know I just it's there's kind of
like a main theme behind a lot of like
this superhero sort of like background
stories hmm like I don't know it I've
always liked the hero stirring stuff
anyway so we've been watching those and
we were watching it last night before
show they went to bed and we had lit a
fire during the day and two birds came
down while watching the Marvel movie and
they came into our living room I was
gonna tell you about that it's crazy
yeah that's what the tech your text was
vague and I was concerned but now Haley
folded under pressure and she's usually
a savage like if there are people
bleeding like if there was a missile
that went off in the back of your like
backyard BBQ she was like you get this
you go I won't she be savage but like
the bird animal rodent thing she's like
not a fan of she was just folded on your
pressure bro she sucked sucked
yeah I mean she's great and every other
aspect with that area she just sucked at
him cool yeah but yet so that we've been
watching maro fans okay so what have you
been watching well you're going back to
you know I there have been like select
ones that I've watched that I have
enjoyed like as movies and entertainment
like I don't like I've never liked
Klingons like a I have to go you know I
never like really felt that polar
anything but I'm like I'm terribly picky
about like what I watch and stuff I'm
gonna like watch a series but like I
came across on HBO there's a series
called The Outsider
there's based on like a Stephen King
book I think but it's like one of those
things were cinematically it's shot
artistically kind of like that Chernobyl
series like it's just very like it's
just really thoughtful stuff and the
first few episodes
it's like variable it seems like you're
watching just the most brutal murder
mystery and then it kind of turns
supernatural and you like yeah and then
by the end of it you're like I believe
it like yeah it's really cool it's
really cool how it ropes you and I think
I watched the whole series in like two
or three days well I mean one season of
it and it's good it's really interesting
you'd recognize some of the actors from
other things but what platform settle
what I mean it's on it HBO so like I did
it from like the Xfinity go stuff but I
think you can still stream it from other
services like it's on like Amazon like
that but other than that like I you know
the your mom's house podcast community
like Tom Segar and his wife Christina P
like they have their podcast every
Wednesday dr. drew after dark on ymh has
an episode with either Christina or Tom
every Friday and then two bears one cave
every Sunday mm-hmm so like that's I
look forward to that everybody like he
knows three times a week why my call I'm
gonna laugh and enjoy myself no like I'm
looking forward to going home tonight
and I'm gonna eat dinner and watch two
bears one cave okay so I'm stoked like I
love laughing and stuff I just like the
long-form podcast stuff I'm into I'm so
cool like you like you know if you're
the thing but it's like you get to kind
of like in a way hang out with two
people that like out if they were there
you'd probably just like [__] and
right alongside them sure I mean I like
to think occupying space even you know
which is totally fine I mean I'm silent
I could occupy his movie Jay
me completely something I would be Jamie
but I feel like I don't know it's just
it's simple stuff and they've
intentionally increased their content
due to coronavirus because they were
deemed essential media and so they able
to still continue doing the stuff with
their staff and so they're intentionally
ramping calm and because they're
stand-up comedians so they can't work so
the revenue is podcast base right now
but and but yeah it's just simple funny
stuff like that other than that though I
I've started to tell myself when I can't
find something to watch that I'm
supposed to be listening to music mm-hmm
so trying to like up my music listening
in general setting change yeah okay give
okay so like would you go to Spotify
because I feel like a lot of people just
like you need to go to their likes and
hit shuffle where they go to just like
the pop whatever which is fun whatever
you like is there's a lot of cool music
but like there's there's a lot of cool
ways to discover some [__] mmm yeah it
it's you used to be easier I feel like
not like like before Spotify here I feel
like when I was younger discovering new
bands like it was more bountiful I'm
Spotify you know I would just say pick
an artist that you enjoy and when you
finish their top songs or their
discography even it starts playing
related music from there and just you
can kind of sift through that the
discovery weekly playlist Spotify does
stuff for you every Monday that's been
really cool I found a lot of good stuff
from them from that but the main thing
is just every time you hear something
you like make sure you press the heart
button you know serious more yeah cuz
it'll start you know directing at that
but in that area and that genre and
stuff but I think I know the on the
desktop version specifically you can go
to like fans also like or like or sounds
like or something like that there's a
tab so I gif you're like like gee otic
for example I like I like his music and
so I clicked on fans or sounds like or
fans also like and there's this artist
named golden panda or gold panda no I
was like cool what and he does similar
music but even more mellow and I was
like great another layer lower I'm I'm
I'm really
into it and so then I was cool then
there was this other artist I think the
artist is tourists and they died like
it's an album that I've like skipped
over so many times and I've liked listen
to it finally and there's like eight
songs that are absolutely perfect like
it's like it's like ambient house it's
really cool like like where the kick
drum is not a big massive sound it's
like more of like a like a palm on a car
seat
mmm you know yeah so like a just like
feel this like slow kinetic McCarthy
yeah yeah just a little little fluffier
great so anyway yeah I feel it yeah but
I mean I I don't know I tried to be in
front of screens too much right now I am
I'm in front of a lot of them but yeah I
mean you gotta you gotta make an effort
to like you know when you're like oh
shoot you know what maybe I don't need
to watch something else I'm gonna go
yeah for a while I could play some music
or listen to music and just like I don't
know I just the you know create digging
of sorts that we can do on Spotify and
on YouTube instead of just like clicking
on links and following and like oh I
like that BAM let's check out their old
stuff and would they play with and
whatever just following those those are
kind of like some I know I guess other
other kind of healthy things you could
be doing instead of just watching a ton
of Netflix if that's you know one thing
I like about band camp is like they
don't do what I understand there's not
much of an algorithm like if you're
listening to like cuz most the stuff on
Bandcamp is already niche that's very
like obscure genre stuff so it's like
let's say you listening to like a post
rock band like an ambient instrumental
band as opposed to like playing
something that has a lot of plays that's
similar it will just continue playing
stuff that is for sure that genre hmm
which is that which i think is really
cool it's like but that's one of the
reasons why I think we had success on
band camp because we had some success
that was outside of calots County and
it's not because we got added into
something you don't I mean we got
featured on the front page at one point
I was like new psych new something for
like a few hours and that got a 500
clicks quick and that was cool but it's
just I don't know it's just so actually
how like that like those are realistic
numbers like it's just like and the
impact is cool but it's like in the
reality of it like 500 does not have an
impact on you financially
career-wise right it's but a crowd of
500 be insane
so it's yeah imagine dude back on the
day like if you if you had 50 people
around you like people are like hey
what's going on over there
like anybody would be like they'd be
like what we trust fifty people who are
tapping their foot we like this but yeah
like that's all it could take sometimes
it's the the numbers thing is new and it
started with SoundCloud and it
progressed to the whole entire business
past that this didn't used to affect
stuff like the world of jazz music all
all like the most famous jazz musicians
in the world still have like less than a
thousand listeners in spotify monthly
right it's a really bizarre it's just
because it's because it doesn't really
mean anything it's like it's it's a it's
unfortunately a social stature and I
click among musicians as what's turned
into that's exactly what it is it's no
longer a platform to share stuff it's
become social stature among other
musicians to respect you because you had
a lot of plays to and like like I mean
like like the amount of like messages or
replies we got because we just all of a
sudden it it's it's there's some it's
not cool a bunch of algorithms no no
like like like just people reaching out
like hey I started got these numbers
like remember if you ever want to blow
blow we can it's like you didn't reply
to me when I like was reaching out so
like get you booked for a show in
Longview Washington antidote Tap House
it's just you saw numbers and you're
like how can I be a part of that mmm my
answer is like you can't and numbers
complicated everything yeah they just
like be good just be a good creator and
a personally accounts everything
sure does it'll be nice when you could
just like okay here's how big you get
Eric just this will be your goal to
where you don't have to [__] look at
social media ever again you could just
play music with Jake and Jake
I mean I'll have to be as big as Garth
Brooks come on with Brooks yeah who are
they still going on the Garth Brooks
thing like at least they talk about all
the time it's really good if you're on
if go to Instagram pull up Garth Brooks
and notice that all of his comments on
every photo is people saying like
release the children like my family and
these answers and stuff like that
because Tom Segura and the ymh crew has
like started this very believable thing
that like Garth Brooks has detached from
reality he has too much money everything
he's saying is a lie he dyes his beard
too dark he's living a lie he's he's
filled with quiet rage what yeah he
probably has people captive
okay like respondent any this is so far
I don't think so it's gonna get like
stuck or [__] but I mean but like Tom
Segura said like they're going through
graphs and sir gravity's like this is
still my biggest accomplishment dude and
he was like genuine he's like this
brings me more joy than my children like
dude that I just feel like in this weird
world I mean I guess it comedians are
definitely always making sure to push
the edge like right of reality almost
like look at like like no like it like
crystalline Christa I was [__] his
last name da Lea Christie alias either
way hold on I'm not gonna I'm not gonna
attempt it no or like Dave Chappelle's
or just the more recent ones they're
just pointing out like like when when a
Erica - thing I was talking about in
podcast and it really did make me think
when Dave Chappelle broke the wall of he
was like you know what [__] sucks your
home of the [__] is I think when he was
talking about the audience like oh yeah
I mean he's like breaks the third wall
if he's like he's like you guys suck
like has an audience you suck like
you're doing these things to the
comedian's in here yeah I think I'm
talking about all the political [__] or
whatever but it's just interesting like
you know we see it as like this like you
know extra thing like oh they're coming
and that's what they want to do but like
damn man if we didn't have the gesture
if we can have the Joker if we didn't
have like the the comedian like who
knows how sticking our butts we'd be
like cuz sometimes people get so caught
up in all the [__] we have comedians
people like pulling out like you know in
memes you know I like to point out that
hey like we're overthinking this [__] or
yeah you got to stop sucking or whatever
I think I think a huge like comedians
right now more than ever are like super
important and stuff and they're already
getting popular because of podcast but
now it's like they're the ones are kind
of carrying you through as far as mental
health I mean the ymh community is like
one of the main reasons why like because
like people are on reddit or they're on
Twitter tweeting and posting like jokes
instead I mean you're yeah and your
party's inside jokes that feels fun but
you just don't feel as alone all of a
sudden mmm and but yet you're still
comfortable being alone you're just
doing that it's it's a there's been a
weird
several weeks man
I know well so yeah cuz I remember I had
a comedian scheduled on he had a friend
of mine who was gonna come on we're
going to talk about comedy and stuff oh
cool but I don't know I might end up
doing these I might do this I'm not sure
I just want to make sure it's like a
watch daily to be able to come home
everyday from from work and not feel
like perhaps she's contaminated now from
at home - I know I just want to keep it
just complete I don't know I just and I
have a lot of anxiety myself around it
like who knows what the [__] is real
with the news cycles now and and just
want to take extra precaution so I mean
I've been canceling the podcast I may
end up doing this
I'll get the my comedian friends back on
I have a couple other people that were
scheduled you should um sharek we will
do I mean we hang out enough we'll
definitely do a couple more we've been
doing we've had a couple successful
backyard social distance hangs where I
think we could you make this work if
like just content needs to happen like
at least every once in a while and stuff
or it you know but then you and Spencer
did one recently - right like with the
video call stuff right yeah that's
pretty cool
let's get that I don't love it as much I
I mean it's okay he works it's okay it's
it's a way to adapt for now yeah yeah
it's hard to though it's just like it's
it's it I just feel like I'm grounded
all the time right now like I feel like
I'm in middle school and I'm grounded
you're not allowed to go see so and so
you not allowed to do this and you can't
do it it's like I wanna go to the beach
know what I wanna go to our story and
have Thai food at the food trucks no
yeah I heard that there's a bit cracking
down at the its yeah I did it's a lot
like I actually drove to the beach last
week and I was like I'm just gonna try
to break on like parkland ministry just
go over I dune nope there's like they
patrol hard oh they told you leave oh no
no I just didn't even attempt it oh
there's not much patrol around oh yeah
and they also have like like like local
volunteers who are just like going
around they're deputized nice like all
or whatever that's weird yeah so just
because it because like right well
people swarmed the beaches and like
residents were like screw all of you I
don't blame them I get that yeah I'll
blame them I don't land on one but
somebody's got to protect it I suppose a
weird thing such a weird time dude
I appreciate you coming over man I
appreciate you coming to hang and talk a
little bit about roasts and talk a
little bit about that man
it's just casual stuff just good to be
outside of the house honestly yeah yeah
and like I said like it's just I think
it was important to just like say things
are more updated because everything was
like so excited to play these shows in
the last podcast we recorded it's like
there aren't those we recorded so that
one and then I I have one more but I
recorded that it was like right before
lockdown yeah so we didn't know that
that was because they remember it
shifted it was like one or two days like
a half it was like all something oh [__]
this is weird
look we are staying home things are
canceled but so it but I had I think
I've explained this in an intro but I've
had I had them back locked and I planned
on during my audio director work doing
it I'm in hotel rooms and on planes and
stuff so I was trying to a bunch of
podcasts back to back but I can still do
just a weekly it'd be back dated but
it'd be no big deal because it's like
what can I do I'm traveling right but
now it just is kind of weird and I
didn't want am i crushing out and
whatever so I'll try to do some more
listeners take care of yourself
check out ROS tan on Spotify and yeah
yeah
uh yeah social media on everything is
just at ROS tan band at roast and then
and then uh yeah just I don't know I'd
be well be safe think of others and take
care of yourself excellent love you
brother
love you too man
you